Pietro Mattei

Recruitment Specialist IT & Digital at IKEA

+46 736565156

Malmö, Sweden

pietromattei@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pietromattei/

SUMMARY

Personal -

Originally from Italy, based in Sweden for many years, I enjoy my life together with my wife, family, and friends. I'm a people-oriented tech nerd that loves traveling, new cultures, gaming, food and coffee among other things.

Professional -

Five years of experience with technical recruitments, both domestic and global. Experience teaming up with hiring managers and building robust relationships. I value the candidate experience with a people's first mindset. Immense interest in everything tech, from software to hardware, I enjoy keeping up to date with the tech world's latest news and trends.

EDUCATION

2013 - 2017

Bachelor's Degree, IT, Media & Design

Södertörns Högskola, Stockholm, SE Web development (HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Wordpress), UX design, graphic design, video editing and more.

SKILLS

Technical Recruitments

Sourcing

LinkedIn Recruiter

Stakeholder Management

LANGUAGES

English

Swedish

Italian

Spanish

CERTIFICATIONS

PI Behavioral Assessment - PREDICTIO

MAP/Matrigma/MINT, Interview technique and competence-based work - Certified in Assessios tools for personal assessment and work performance - Assessio

Black Belt in Internet Recruitment - SocialTalent

WORK EXPERIENCE

2020-09 - presen

Recruitment Specialist IT & Digital

IKEA, Malmö, SE

Building teams within Data & Analytics, Cyber Security, and Data Privacy. Mainly recruiting in Amsterdam, Madrid, and Malmö.

Other activities: Driving Junior Data Engineer Accelerator program from recruitment perspective. Facilitating recruitment training for new hiring managers, deep diving into IKEA way of recruitment.

2019-09 - 2020-07

Tech Recruitment Consultant

Randstad Technologies, Göteborg, SE

As a recruitment consultant, I have a 360 role. The position focuses on building strong relationships with cutting edge tech companies and attracting proficient candidates in the rapidly growing IT market.

2019-06 - 2019-09

Tech Recruiter

Randstad Technologies, Göteborg, SE

Dfind IT changed its name to Randstad Technologies. The same great people still doing amazing stuff. Working at Randstad Technologies I continued my mission: helping companies to grow their technical teams with hard to find developers.

2018-11 - 2019-06

Tech Recruiter

Dfind IT, Göteborg, SE

Tech recruitment with a special focus on various software development roles helping exciting companies in Gothenburg to grow.

2017-08 - 2018-11

Talent Manager

Dfind IT, Göteborg, SE

As a Talent Manager, my mission was to expand our network of skilled, talented tech candidates in Gothenburg. My primary tasks involved headhunting, interviewing, attending various events like university fairs, and supporting with the ongoing recruitment processes.